Here's where we get into the biggest logic portion.
这部分的逻辑比较复杂
So what we want to do is now make recommendations
我们将根据在上面编写的函数
based on all the functions that we have up above.
向用户推荐电影
So here's the way that I did this.
下面说说我的实现步骤
But again, you could write code in a number of different ways.
当然 你可以用多种不同的方式编写这些代码
So I created this movie_seen for each user and kept
我为每个用户创建了这个 movie_seen
track of which movies were watched by the user.
并跟踪用户看过了哪些电影
So this movie_seen now holds all the movies
movie_seen 存储了用户看过的所有电影
that were watched by the user, and that's important
这很重要
because we don't want to recommend these movies to that user.
因为我们不希望向该用户推荐这些电影
I also went out and I got the closest_neighbors.
我还创建了 closest_neighbors
So I'm basically just getting an ordered list of
它返回的是与这个用户最近邻的
which user IDs are closest to this neighbor, this user.
用户 ID 的有序列表
So you give me a user,
如果你传入一个用户
I'm going to go find the movies they've seen
我将查找该用户看过的电影
and I'm going to go find their closest_neighbors.
并找到他的最近邻
From there, I created this recs thing,
接着 我创建了这个 recs()
which is just an empty NumPy array that I'm going
它是一个空的 NumPy 数组
to assign a whole bunch of things into.
我会向里面添加多项内容
Essentially, what I want to do is
对于 closest_neighbors 中的
for each neighbor in the closest_neighbors,
每个近邻
I am going to get the movies that that neighbor liked.
我将获取该近邻喜欢的电影
So using that function that we just wrote,
我将使用刚刚编写的函数
I'm going to go find the movies that that neighbor liked.
查找该近邻喜欢的电影
So I'm going to say
在这里输入
likes equals movies_liked by neighbor.
neigh_likes = movies_liked(neighbor)
Okay. So this is the neighbors' ID.
Ok这是近邻的 ID
I just passed that in. I'm going to get what they liked.
传入该 ID 并获取近邻喜欢的电影
There's this really nice way to compare to
有一个方法很方便
NumPy arrays and get the ones of the array that aren't in the other.
它可以比较两个 NumPy 数组 并返回在一个数组中但不在另一个里面的值
There's this thing called np.setdiff1d.
这个方法称为 np.setdiff1d()
Essentially, what it does is it takes the first array,
它会获取第一个数组
so what I called neigh_ likes
我称为 neigh_ likes
and it looks at the second array which is this movies_ seen.
然后查看第二个数组 即 movies_ seen
Again, we can make this faster by saying assume_unique equals true.
在这里使用 assume_unique = true 使代码更快
So similar to the intersection function we used before.
与之前使用的intersection() 函数相似
But this is going to take the difference between
这个函数将查看两个数组之间的差异
these two arrays and basically give me back
并返回一个新的数组
a new array that holds all of the movies
其中包含在这个数组里
that are in this one that aren't in this one.
但不在这个数组里的所有电影
So it's going to take the movies that that user liked that this individual
它将提取该用户喜欢的而此用户尚未看过的电影
hasn't seen yet and we're going to set that equal to new_recs.
我们将其设为等于 new_recs
Then what we want to do is concatenate
然后将 new_recs
new_recs with the original recs and make that the recommendations.
与原始 recs 相连并作为推荐内容
So what that looks like is we're going to take the unique values.
我们将获取唯一值
What this is doing is it's concatenating these two arrays
这行代码的作用是将这两个数组连接到一起
together and then it's saying only give me the unique value.
然后仅返回唯一值
So take the new recommendations and the old recommendations,
连接新推荐数组和旧推荐数组
which originally doesn't have anything in it,
旧推荐数组本来里面什么也没有
but it's going to hold more and more stuff as we
但是当我们为每个近邻不断连接新的推荐内容时
keep concatenating new recommendations for each neighbor.
它将存储越来越多的内容
Then we can look at the length of this recs array and if
然后查看这个 recs 数组的长度
it meets the spec of how many recommendations we want to make,
如果已经达到推荐数量上限
then we'll break and we'll hand those recommendations back.
则停止连接并返回这些推荐电影
So if the length of recs is greater than num_recs.
如果 recs 的长度大于 num_recs
I'll just say num_recs minus one, then we'll break,
这里是 num_recs -1 则 break
and our recommendations will be equal to the movie names,
recommendations 将等于 movie_names()
which is why we created that function up there of recs.
这就是我们在上面创建这个函数的原因 然后传入recs
This recs is just going to be all of the IDs.
这个 recs 将是所有的 ID
Whereas, what we want to get back in
而我们想在这个 recommendations 部分
this recommendations portion are actually the movie titles.
获取的是片名
That's what this part does.
也就是这部分的作用